다이간다는 방을 밝게 하고 적당히 떨어져서 봐!
Watch Daigunder in a bright room and keep some distance!
Смотри Дайгандера со включённым светом, сидя подальше от экрана!
다이간다!
Daigunder!
Дайгандер!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе,
마음의 눈을 열어라
Open your eyes of soul
Распахни шире око души
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
(Bakutou Sengen Daigunder)
Боевой претендент Дайгандер!
뜨거운 마음을 담아
With all your hot heart
Пусть меня охватит твой жар сердца,
오늘도 기적을 맹새해
I will make a miracle today too
Чтобы сотворить сумел я чудо
드래곤 소드 작렬이야
Dragon Sword bursts
Вспыхнет ярким светом Меч Дракона!
싸워야 할 라이벌은
The rival I have to fight against is
Побороть я должен свой упавший дух,
좌절하려는 내 자신
right here, dispirited myself
что пути к успеху преграждает мне,
어제보다도 진화해서
Evolve even more than yesterday
Вырасти сегодня больше, чем вчера
강해져라!
And become strong!
И сильнее стать!
다다다다 다 다 다 다다
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
Пушка Дракона!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе
에너지 전개로
Open up all your energy and
Дай энергии выход, сказав...
다다다다다다 다
Dadadadadada da
Дададададада-да!!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
쓰러트려라 타도해라
Defeat and knock down
Победи и врагов одолей
빛나는 강철의
Fighter of shining steel
Сталью сверкает тело твоё,
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
제 22 화
The 22nd Episode
Эпизод 22
망각선언!
Oblivion Declaration!
잃어버린 기억!!
Lost Memories!!
(en: A Battle Down Memory Lane)
여러분 모두 배틀 로봇 팬 모임에 오신 걸 환영합니다!
Everyone, welcome to battle robot fans' meeting!
이번에는 바로 그 알바트로스 리그 챔피언, 팀 아키라가 나와 주셨습니다!
Today, we have Team Akira, the champion of Albatross League!
팀 아키라입니다! 배틀 로봇 광고에는 꼭! 팀 아키라! 저건? 배틀 로봇 껌 사장! 사장님!
Team Akira here! If you need battle robots for a commercial, call us! Team Akira!
Who's that? That must be the head of battle robot gum company! Mister!
그럼 나오십니다! 커맨더 아키라와 불타는 용기사 류구!
They're here! Commander Akira and Burning Dragon Warrior Ryugu!
와, 감사합니다, 감사합니다!
All of you, thank you, thank you!
감사합니다, 감사합니다!
Thank you, thank you!
그럼 바로 물어 봅시다. 팀 아키라의 힘의 비밀은 한 단어로?
Then let me ask right away! What's the secret to the strength of Team Akira, in one word?
-그건 당연히 나야!
-Of course, that's me!
-내가 있으니까야!
-Everything's thanks to me!
이야, 타이밍도 딱! 이 잘 맞는 호흡이 강함의 비밀인가요!
Their timings are perfectly in sync! That must be the secret to their strength!
잠깐, 좀 작작 해라! 다들 내 이야기를 들으러 왔다고!
Hey, don't try to take my position! Everyone's here to listen to my story!
뭔 소리야? 모두가 알고 싶어하는 건 팀 아키라의 비밀, 그러니까 나 말이잖아!
What are you talking about? Everyone wants to know about the secret of Team Akira, and that's me!
뭐야?!
What?!
싸울래?
Wanna fight?
저기... 두 분?
Err... you two?
막! 막을 내려!
The curtain! Drop the curtain!
둘 다 그만해!
Stop it, you two!
둘을 떨어뜨리겠습니다.
We'll take those two apart.
류구는 저희가, 여러분은 아키라 군을!
We'll take Ryugu, and you'll take Akira!
알겠어!
Got it!
이리 와라!
Come this way!
잠깐, 류구! 이번이야말로 끝장내 주겠어!
Stop right there, Ryugu! We'll settle this today!
이거 놔! 난 아키라한테 볼 일이 있어!
Let me go! I have an unfinished business with Akira!
도망치냐, 류구?!
Running away, Ryugu?!
알겠으니까 놔! 놓으라니까!
I get it, so let me go! Unhand me!
쳇, 아키라 놈, 지멋대로긴.
Tch. That Akira is so selfish.
뭐, 뭐야, 니들?
W- who are you guys?
잠깐 자고 있어라.
Take a rest.
뭔 일이야?
What's going on?
대체 뭔 생각이야? 그런 곳에서 싸우기나 하고!
What were you thinking?! Why would you fight on the stage?!
이미지도 나빠지겠고, 이래선 성립될 광고 계약도 깨진다!
You've lowered our image, and that might get in our way while making a commercial contract!
그래도 말야...
But, you know...
어쨌든 두번 다시 없는 기회니까 생각 좀 해라.
Anyway, this is not an everyday chance. Think before you act!
세수라도 하고 머리 좀 식히고 와.
Wash your face, cool your head, and then return.
왜 나만 혼난 거야?
Why was I scolded, but not him?
애초에 류구가 주제넘게 구니까 그런 거잖아!
It's all because Ryugu butted in!
류구!
Ryugu!
멈춰!
Stop!
서둘러!
Hurry!
어디 못 간다!
You aren't going anywhere!
류구! 류구!
Ryugu! Ryugu!
끈질긴 놈!
Persistent brat!
됐다!
That's enough!
류구! 큰일이야, 모두한테 알려야 해!
Ryugu! This is terrible! I gotta let everybody know!
하루카! 하루카!
Haruka! Haruka!
젠장, 부서졌어.
Damn, it broke!
기다려, 류구! 곧장 구해주러 갈게!
Just you wait, Ryugu! I'm going to rescue you!
아키라! 류구! 아키라! 류구!
Akira! Ryugu! Akira! Ryugu!
빨간 여우 절도단?
Red Fox Thief Gang?
유명한 배틀 로봇을 유괴해서 과거의 기억을 지우고 암시장에서 사고 팝니다.
They kidnap famous battle robots, delete their memories, and sell them in black markets.
전국에서 지명수배중인 배틀 로봇 절도단입니다.
They are wanted battle robot thieves.
설마 그 놈들이 절도단이었다니...
I can't believe they were thieves...
아키라도 같이 있을 지 모른다.
Akira might be with them.
우리도 총력을 다해 행방을 쫒겠습니다.
We will chase them with all our capabilities.
큰일이야!
That's so bad!
뭔가 알게 된다면 곧장 연락하겠습니다.
We'll contact you as soon as we find something out.
브라이온, 우리도 나뉘어져 찾아보자.
Bullion, let's divide and find them.
그래.
Got it.
이글 애로!
Eagle Arrow!
맡겨 둬! 관객은 우리가 붙들고 있을게.
Leave it to us! We'll keep the audience busy.
부탁한다.
Do so.
가자, 드리모그!
Let's go, Drimog!
지금이야말로 훈련의 성과를 보여주겠어모그!
We'll show the result of our training today-mogu!
저기구나! 좋아!
There must be it! Well then!
여기에는 없나 봐.
They're not here...
대회에서 우승한 배틀 로봇 뿐이잖아!
They're champion battle robots!
얘들 대체 뭐하는 놈들이야?
Who the heck are those guys?
아까 놈들이다.
The guys I saw before.
그래서 비싸게 팔릴 것 같나?
So, do you think it'll sell in a high price?
에, 지금까지의 10배, 아니, 100배는 가능합니다.
More than 10 times, no, 100 times that we sold before.
그 정도인가.
That much?
그렇구나! 얘들 배틀 로봇을 유괴해서 몰래 팔았구나! 어서 류구를 찾아야겠어!
I see! Those guys kidnapped battle robots and sold to black markets! I must find Ryugu as soon as possible!
류구!
Ryugu!
류구! 류구!
Ryugu! Ryugu!
이게 무슨 끔찍한 짓이야!
How terrible!
뭔 일이냐?
What's going on?
어, 저 놈!
That guy!
류구! 류구!
Ryugu! Ryugu!
잘 됐다! 무사했구나!
That's great! You're safe!
너 누구냐?
Who are you?
들켰다! 가자, 류구!
They found out! Let's go, Ryugu!
가? 간다니 어디에?
Go? To where?
설명은 나중에! 어쨌든 도망쳐!
I'll explain later! Run away for now!
손 대지 마!
Don't touch me!
달콤한 말로 날 데려갈려는 속셈이지? 불타는 용기사 류구는 그 수에는 안 넘어간다!
Aren't you trying to take me with some made-up stories? I, Burning Dragon Warrior Ryugu, do not fall to that!
뭔 소리야, 류구?
What are you talking about, Ryugu?
거리낌 없이 부르지 마!
Don't call me as if I'm your friend!
어?
What?!
어쨌든 여긴 어디냐?
Anyway, where am I?
자, 소용없는 저항은 관두고 순순히 일로 와라.
Resistance is futile. You'd better be obedient and come here.
재밌구나! 뭔지는 모르겠지만 상대해 주겠어!
Interesting! I don't know what's going on here, but I'll face you!
관둬, 류구! 이 놈들을 상대하면...
Forget it, Ryugu! If you fight them...
나한테 명령하지 마!
Do not order me!
잡아라!
Get them!
나이트 슬래시!
Knight Slash!
흥, 별 것 아닌 놈들이군.
Hmph. They're easy.
물량으로 승부할 생각이냐?
You're trying to win by numbers?
류구! 여기야!
Ryugu! This way!
쫒아!
Get them!
가라! 도망치게 두지 마라!
Go! Do not let them escape!
끈질긴 놈들!
How persistent of them!
저기다! 쫒아!
That way! Get them!
저런! 막장이야!
No! It's an end of the road!
멈춰라!
Stop!
젠장, 이걸 어째!
Damn, where should we go?
역시 할 수 밖에 없군.
I really have to do this.
류구!
Ryugu!
여기야!
This way!
나는 불타는 용기사 류구야! 그런 곳에 숨을까 보냐!
I am Burning Dragon Warrior Ryugu! No way I'm hiding in there!
됐으니까 와!
Just come!
도망은 빠른 놈들! 찾아! 찾아라!
They're fast in running! Find them! Get them!
어떻게든 따돌린 모양이야. 일단 안심이네.
We got lost of them for now. That's a relief.
뭐가 안심이야?! 이런 곳에 밀어 떨어뜨리고!
You call this a relief? You pushed me off into here!
어쩔 수 없잖아?
It couldn't be helped!
흥, 맘대로 해라. 이 앞에 뭐가 있을 지는 모르지만 앞으로 조심해라.
Hmph, whatever. Just be careful from now on, as we don't know what'll be waiting for us.
야, 어디 가, 류구?
Hey, where are you going, Ryugu?
어디라도 상관 없잖아? 너하고 상관 없는 이야기야.
No matter where I'm going to, it has nothing to do with you.
자, 잠깐, 류구!
H- hey, wait, Ryugu!
아직 뭐 있냐?
You still have something to tell?
뭐 있냐니, 당연하잖아! 모두한테 돌아가야지!
Something? Of course! We have to go back!
팀 아키라의 이야기를 듣고 싶어하는 사람들이 기다리고 있어!
People who want to hear about Team Akira are waiting for us!
팀 아키라? 뭔 소리야.
Team Akira? What are you talking about?
너, 날 누군가하고 착각하고 있는 거 아냐? 난 무적의 배틀 로봇, 류구야!
Aren't you confusing me with someone else? I am the invincible battle robot, Ryugu!
류, 류구...
R- Ryugu...
너...
Did you really...
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
류구, 너 정말 나 기억 안 나? 같이 타이탄 클라우더를 따기로 했잖아!
Ryugu, don't you remember me? We were going to obtain Titan Clouder together!
알바트로스 리그에서 같이 싸웠어! 그걸, 그걸 전부 잊었다는 거야?
We fought together in Albatross League! And you're saying that you forgot everything?
시끄러운 놈이네.
What a noisy guy.
모르는 건 몰라. 뭔 소리인지 전혀 모르겠어.
I can't know what I don't know. I don't understand you at all.
류구...
Ryugu...
찾았다!
There they are!
그렇게 간단히 달아나게 둘 거라고는 생각하지 않았는데 말이야.
I knew they won't let us get away that easily.
좀 상처 입어도 상관 없다.
You can make some injuries to them.
잡아라!
Get them!
잠깐, 류구!
Stop, Ryugu!
나이트 슬래시!
Knight Slash!
류구, 오른쪽이야!
Ryugu, on your right!
말 안 해도 알아!
You don't have tell me everything!
위야! 피해!
Up! Evade!
시끄러워!
Shut up!
류구!
Ryugu!
네가 조잘조잘대니까 집중 안 돼! 입 닫고 있어!
You are making me unable to concentrate! Shut your mouth!
류구!
Ryugu!
가라!
Go!
나이트 퀘이크!
Knight Quake!
흥, 결국 날 상대할 수 있는 놈들이 아니야.
Hmph. They aren't my enemies.
네, 네이놈!
Y- you bastard!
류구!
Ryugu!
저런 거에 휩쓸리면 끝이야!
If he falls into that, it's all over!
아슬아슬했네. 이제 괜찮아!
It was close. It's alright now!
너...
You...
놔. 이대로라면 둘 다 휩쓸려.
Let me go. Or you're gonna fall too.
그렇게 되면 그렇게 되는 거지!
If that happens, well, that happens!
바보야! 어서 놔!
Idiot! Unhand me!
안 놔! 절대!
I will never let you go! Never!
뭐?! 달아났다고?!
What?! They ran away?!
에잇, 이 쓸모없는 놈!
How useless of you!
하수가 흘러가는 곳은 이 지점.
The sewage heads to this point.
보스! 놈들이 어디 있는지 찾아냈습니다!
Boss! I found out where they are!
-정말이냐?
-틀림없습니다.
-Really?
-No doubt about it!
-이번에야말로 잡아라!
-잠시 기다리쇼.
-Get them this time no matter what!
-Just a moment.
일단 류구에게선 아키라의 기억을 지웠습니다. 제게 좋은 생각이.
I already removed the memories about Akira from Ryugu. I have an idea.
일단 살았네.
We lived anyhow.
정말, 무리하기는. 한 발짝이라도 잘못 디뎠으면 너도 가라앉았다.
You're really overdoing it. If you made one wrong step, then you might have sunk too.
뭐, 됐잖아! 결국 둘 다 살았고 말야.
Well, it's all over! We end up living.
너...
You...
찾았구나, 류구!
We found you, Ryugu!
-저 놈들!
-아까 놈들이냐?
-Those guys!
-Are those the one from before?
자, 류구! 돌아와라! 아버지에게!
Ryugu! Come back to your father!
뭐?!
What?!
너는 이 닥터가 만든 최고의 걸작! 내게는 자식과 마찬가지!
You are the ultimate masterpiece that I made! You are just like my son!
이상한 소리 집어치워! 류구는 우리 할아버지가 만든 배틀 로봇이야!
Don't be stupid! Ryugu is a battle robot that my grandfather made!
아니다!
That is not true!
어떻게 된 거야.
What's going on?
기억 못 하니! 네 아버지를!
Don't you remember your father?
모든 건 저 얘 잘못이다. 메인터넌스 중인 너를 훔쳐 나온 저 녀석이!
It's all his fault. He stole you during your maintenance!
정말이야?
Is it true?
저들이 말하는 거.
About what they're saying.
류구!
Ryugu!
아무 말이나 둘러대기는! 네놈들이 류구를 훔친 장본인이잖아!
Don't make up some weird story! You're the ones who stole Ryugu at the first place!
자, 류구! 돌아와라!
Ryugu! Come back!
가면 안 돼, 류구!
You must not go, Ryugu!
류구!
Ryugu!
조심해!
Watch out!
나이트 퀘이크!
Knight Quake!
저런!
Oh no!
저 놈들!
Those guys!
그런 것이었구나!
Now I see everything!
들킨 이상 어쩔 수 없군. 덤벼들어라!
As he found out, it can't be helped. Get them!
류구!
Ryugu!
놈들이 노리는 건 이 나야. 넌 거기에 있어.
They're looking for me. You can stay there.
나이트 슬래시!
Knight Slash!
류구, 뒤야!
Ryugu, on your back!
좋아, 류구!
Good job, Ryugu!
내빼지 말고 가라!
Go get them!
점프해, 류구!
Jump, Ryugu!
뭐?
What?
등판해!
Go up!
지금이야! 나이트 슬래시!
Now! Use Knight Slash!
나이트 슬래시!
Knight Slash!
좋아, 류구! 그렇게 계속!
You're doing great, Ryugu! Keep it on!
뭐지? 이 감각은. 저 녀석하고의 일체감은.
What is this feeling? What is this sense of unity with him?
뭘 하나! 어서 잡아라!
What are you doing? Just get them already!
뒤에서 온다! 피해! 이제 오른쪽!
Incoming from your back! On your right!
이 감각. 몸이, 검이 자연히 움직이는 것 같은 이 감각.
This feeling. As if my body and my sword are moving so naturally.
쟤는... 대체 누구지?
Who is him, really?
네이놈... 아키라다! 아키라를 잡아라!
Damn you... It's Akira! Get Akira!
아키라...
Akira...
아키라!
Akira!
괜찮아, 아키라?
Are you okay, Akira?
날 기억해 냈구나!
You finally remembered me!
뭔 소리야! 내가 아키라를 잊어버릴 리가-
What are you saying? I would never forget about you, Akira-
류구!
Ryugu!
지금이다! 잡아라!
Now! Get them!
뭐야?!
What?!
누구야, 쟤들?
Who are they?
네이놈! 저 놈들부터 먼저 처리해라!
Those bastards! Get rid of them first!
파이터 체인지야!
They did Fighter Change!
마그마 다이나믹!
Magma Dynamic!
블리자드 로드!
Blizzard Rod!
대, 대단해!
T- they're awesome!
뭔 힘이야!
What power they have!
아키라!
Akira!
기다렸어!
I've been waiting!
류구! 건더! 헤드합체!
Ryugu! Gunder! Head Fusion!
폭투왕 다이간다!
Wild Fight King Daigunder!
클러스터 파워 전개!
Activate Cluster Power!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
공격!
Attack!
해냈어!
We did it!
퇴각! 퇴각!
Retreat! Retreat!
어딜 가나.
You're not going anywhere.
포기해라! 빨간 여우단!
Give it up, Red Fox Gang!
봐 주세요!
Forgive us!
쟤들... 대체 누구였지?
Who were they?
보아하니 류구는 기억 회로가 절단되었었나 봐.
It seems that Ryugu's memory circuits have been cut.
그래서 날 잊었던 거구나.
So that's why he forgot me!
그래. 그래도 서봇이 수리했으니까 걱정하지 마. 다만 유괴된 이후의 기억은 대신 없어지지만.
Yeah, but don't worry since Supbot repaired him. But instead, he lost his memories after being kidnapped.
그래도, 그거 이상하지 않아? 그 설명으로는 류구가 날 기억하는 건 불가능하잖아?
But isn't that weird? That means Ryugu cannot possibly remember me, right?
착각 아니야?
Wasn't it just you?
그럴 리가 없어! 다이간다로 합체도 했고.
That's impossible! He even combined into Daigunder.
그건... 어쨌든, 그럴 리 없어. 류구가 아키라를 기억해 내다니.
That's... anyway, impossible. Ryugu couldn't remember about you, Akira.
그런가...
Maybe that's true...
류구! 괜찮아?
Ryugu! Are you alright?
어, 왠지 걱정하게 해서 미안해!
Yeah, sorry for making you worried!
있잖아, 너 정말 아무것도 기억 안 나?
Hey, don't you really remember anything?
그게 전혀.
Not at all.
말했지?
I told you.
음, 역시 내 착각이었나.
Maybe it really was my imagination.
내가 기억하는 건, 팬 모임에 불려가서...
What I remember is that we were in a fan meeting...
팬 모임?
Fan meeting?
아, 잊었다!
I completely forgot!
몰랐어... 쟤들 저런 재능이 있었다니.
I never knew they have talent like that.
나도...
Me too...
나도.
Me too.
그럼 다시 소개합니다!
Let us introduce them again!
아, 맞아, 아키라. 고맙다고 말하는 걸 잊었네.
Oh, right, Akira, I forgot to tell you thanks.
고맙다니?
Thanks?
하수도에서 말야. 아키라가 구해주지 않았으면 빠졌을 지도 모르니까.
At the sewers. If you didn't save me, Akira, I might have really been sunk.
커맨더 아키라하고 불타는 용기사 류구!
Commander Akira and Burning Dragon Warrior Ryugu!
뭐 해, 아키라! 어서 와!
What are you doing, Akira? Hurry up and come!
어...
Err...
어!
Yeah!
끝없는 꿈을 꾸고 있어
Dreaming an endless dream
Я сон бесконечный вижу опять перед собой
몇번이고 쓰러져도
I fall down over and over again
Как упал, и лечу вниз вновь и вновь.
저 구름 위에는 분명히
Up over those clouds
Там, где-то в высотах, за чертой облаков
푸른 하늘이 펼쳐져 있을 거야
a blue sky awaits
голубое небо ждёт меня!
강해지기 위해서라면 누구도 혼자서는
To be strong, nobody can ever become
Сильным быть, чтоб никто превзойти не смог
강해지고 뜨거워질 수 없어
strong and hot, by oneself
Стать сильней, горячей, сам я хочу!
불꽃의 Fight Fight Fighting soul
Flaming fightin' fightin' fighting soul
Так гори, душа, душа бойца!
용기를 마주치는 그 때
When you face your courage
Смелость повстречай, и пусть ведёт она тебя в жизни.
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
느껴져 바로 너라는 게
I can feel it, yes, it's you
Я это чувствую, да, это ты!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
둘은 서로의 영웅
The two are heroes of each other
Два героя - части одного, нерушимы связи,
질 수 없는 같은 내일을
They run towards to the same tomorrow
Вместе в новый день по одной тропе спешат
바라보고 달려
that they cannot lose
И не собьются с неё!
다음 에피소드 예고
Preview for Next Episode
우리를 구해준 드라고플레임하고 드라고프리저.
Dragoflame and Dragofreezer rescued us.
놈들을 만든 건 할아버지였어!
It's my grandfather who made them!
좋아, 언젠가 꼭 쟤들을 동료로 만들어 보이겠어!
Well then, I'll make them become my comrades!
그 때, 갑자기 다이랜드에 불덩어리가 떨어졌어!
But then, a fireball has fallen to Dailand!
넌 대체...
Who are you?
폭투선언 다이간다의 다음 이야기!
전설선언! 암흑수 드라고버스트 탄생!!
Next time on Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
Legend Declaration! The Birth of Dark Beast Dragoburst!